# Leonardo Faria

Software engineer with broad experience designing, architecting, and developing websites and SaaS products. Growth-minded and passionate about building 0 to 1 products through thoughtful stakeholder engagements, deep technical expertise, and an eye for scaling processes and people.

**Core competencies:** Front-end, technical leadership, architecture, mentorship, Continuous Integration, Design System, accessibility, Developer Experience

## Experience

#### Lattice

#### San Francisco / Remote

#### Apr 2022 — Present

## **Staff Software Engineer**

- Worked on different 0 to 1 projects from a new company initiative with TypeScript and React, iterating and adapting the product according to requirements/customer needs
- Improved testing by creating documentation, guidelines and building a CI tool to track test coverage across different teams
- Enhanced developer experience tools and documentation, making engineers more productive
- Advocated for accessibility by leveraging automated tests to create a product usable for all customers

Thinkific Vancouver

#### **Technical Architect - Front-end**

Sep 2020 — Mar 2022

- Improved Front-end performance by: introducing Lighthouse testing in CI; refactoring the product to support webp and working on different projects to improve page load and user experience
- Worked closely with teams to demonstrate the feasibility of technical solutions in upcoming projects, bridging product and engineering
- Partnered with the Chief Architect defining technical vision and technical strategy
- Supported the Design System solution (used by different React and Ruby on Rails applications), especially in CI and accessibility tasks

#### **Engineering Team Lead**

Oct 2017 — Sep 2020

- Led a team of up to 7 back-end/front-end engineers working on projects for different customer personas (course creators/students)
- Provided mentorship, collected and delivered feedback; set goals for engineer reports and conducted performance reviews
- Owned projects end-to-end, including the redesign of the product, React adoption, and the creation of the Thinkific Design System (2018 — present)
- Grew the team by proactively sourcing ICs. Successfully recruited 4 engineers by partnering with the HR department and working on creative ways to find talent
- Led different initiatives in R&D (All-hands, onboarding of new members, hackathons) while the company scaled from 50 to 300 employees

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Nov 2016 — Oct 2017

Worked on different customer-facing projects mostly focusing on front-end and using Ruby on Rails and Ember.js

## **Dynamic Leap Technology**

## Full Stack Developer (contract work)

Feb 2016 — Nov 2016

Vancouver

- Developed websites using WordPress for Dynamic Leap and its clients
- Built MVPs for clients using Ember.js and Ruby on Rails APIs.

604media Vancouver

### Full Stack Developer (contract work)

Oct 2015 — Jan 2016

- Maintained Intranet applications (PHP/Laravel) and WordPress websites for agency clients
- Maintained iOS/Android apps built with Phonegap

## **Ministry of Social Security**

Brasilia, Brazil

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Sep 2011 — Aug 2015

- Developed and maintained new and legacy Intranet applications used by thousands of civil servants in Brazil between 2011 - 2018
- Developed the Ministry of Social Security website using WordPress (still in use by millions of citizens)
- Created one of the first iOS and Android apps in the public sector using Cordova

## Education

## **Deque University**

Online

Web Accessibility Curriculum 2.0

2020

## Langara College

Vancouver

Web and Mobile App Development / Post-Degree Diploma

2015 — 2016

### **Pitagoras University**

Brazil

**Bachelor of Information Systems** 

2006 - 2011

## Other

### **Ladies Learning Code**

Vancouver

Instructed HTML & CSS for Beginners and WordPress for Beginners as a volunteer

2017 — 2019

#### Speaker

Vancouver

Spoke in different meetups and conferences. Slides in <a href="https://leonardofaria.net/talks">https://leonardofaria.net/talks</a>

2015 — Present

## Technical Skills

- Front end: React, TypeScript, Next.js, Chakra UI, Tailwind CSS, Ember.js, Storybook, axe, Jest
- Back end: Node.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, Posgres, MySQL
- Other Technologies: Lighthouse, Supabase, graphQL, REST, WordPress
- Tools: Figma, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Circle Cl, Datadog, Grafana
- Infrastructure: AWS, Vercel, Netlify, Fastly